[Music]
w
ah
[Music]
good evening good day everybody Welcome
to the latest episode of the ask abijit
show I hope you're all doing great so as
always before we begin before we get
into the questions let me see who all is
on the live chat I can see let me greet
some of you I can see vinit sa jit Forum
kacha vun Singh Malik Imran naimi from
sou South turkistan hello nand Goan Pros
T zubon eung netian John Smith random
skull pratik Vora jant tanay Desh Pandi
Amisha Mishra aradhya and Avinash somia
jit Rohit Jang hukla G Migel di y rajes
Sharma shanan am at 2K wats photography
Ajay Kumar akula
AA sain giri J Desai Matrix dios pitra
om prash red om prash red niharika Banda
shagun Chopra threat Ripper red
Terminator geopolitical dub Ashish
vishak
Karma shivakumar
midam alien frog Yash Singh Malik s from
Maharashtra hello vnav P Arijit banerji
anupam jwal niharika again internet
gutam SG rakit Dr J Shankar hello DJ
kamat hello from Bengal jet Atul radhika
Trinity anit mahapatra goel rajat 46
Manoj
Shas Kush sha Vishnu om prash aritra
deogi the tradable
and so many other people Sak
sakshar lwig lwig 59 debaker World vinit
Mishra pritam and everybody else okay I
won't greet all of you individually
otherwise we'll do that all day so thank
you so much for being on this live
stream I hope you're doing great now
let's get into the question so this is a
completely live chat live chat Q&A
session ask me your questions in the
live chat and I shall answer those
questions from the live chat itself so
that's the kind of session this is so
let's go let us see what questions you
have let's take some of the older
questions uh as in the questions
answered at the asked at the very
beginning let's see what do we
have let us see let us see let's
begin
um Sonia Sinha says what's your opinion
about project 2025 in the US not sure
I've heard of it I of project 2024 which
is the elections 25 I'm not so sure
maybe I'll read up something about
it
okay 2K wats photography says Russian
fighter jets are not the most
sophisticated and advanced as compared
to their us counterparts how does this
does this affect India considering we
have lots of military Russian military
aircraft with us well who are our
opponents who are our adversaries we
have two major aders Aries the real
adversary is China and then the other
one is Pakistan which is a sto of other
nations it is what it is right now what
kind of fighter planes do they have the
pakistanis their best fighter planes are
the f-16s which are the 1970s 1980s
fighter plane which with upgrades and
all that the Americans will keep on
upgrading that for the pakistanis I'm
sure they've done that reasonably
reasonably recently the Chinese have the
j20 which is the fifth generation
fighter plane um and various other
Russian derived fighter planes as well
so when it comes to India's adversaries
opponents Etc they don't have the most
sophisticated fighter plates uh the j20
obviously it's it's kind of stealy from
the front but not stealy from the back
and so on there are such issues and so
on so what India needs is yeah sure
maybe we don't have the best fighter
planes right now not the most
sophisticated Cutting Edge fighter
planes we have the Tas we have the Suk
we have the the Miraj and the Jaguars
and I don't know what else right so the
thing is
you got to do you got to do the best of
what you have so I would say India
should invest in large numbers of figh
bles they don't need to be the most
sophisticated oh we also have the Mig
21s right and Mig
209s and whatnot a whole zoo a whole
galaxy of different kinds of fighter
planes so if you don't have the biggest
budget if you don't have the most
advanced assets invest in large
quantities of assets quantity has a
quality of its own like Joseph St used
to say so look look uh the Russian
fighter planes are also good it's not
like they're terrible okay uh sure the
Americans have the best ones let's let's
give it to them I agree but it doesn't
mean the Russians have poor fighter
planes the Su are reasonably good the
Jaguars are good the Miis are good the
Rafal are good yes very good fight the
Plains and so on and we we have the Tas
as well so we should invest in quantity
as opposed to Quality and we have
certain advantages the Chinese don't
have Visa the altitude and the Tibetan
plateau and all that which I'll not go
into right now so it's not like we are
hamstrung by the quality of assets we
have we have reasonably good assets the
Russian fighter are not bad so we just
need to utilize them judiciously and
maybe acquire larger quantities maybe
another another 36 raal maybe another 72
Rafal maybe a whole production line in
India and obviously longterm we do
invest in our own technology which is
the
pages mark to the advanced medium combat
aircraft and whatnot whatever comes
after
that so that's what India should
do okay Imran naimi from from Southern
turkistan says the ancient name of
Afghanistan was Arana and there's a
state in India which is harana they have
similar names are they related to each
other I'm not sure they are related to
each other the actual ancient name of
Afghanistan is gandhar that's a name
that's thousand of years old that's the
original name of Afghanistan how did it
acquire the name
Arana well I think it's because of the
iranic connection which comes in kind of
later compared to the gandhar name and
it
it kind of claims that this is the land
of the Arya the so ancient India was
called araa the land of the Arya people
not an ethnic name but no nobility the
AR the word Arya means Noble
in Sanskrit and the Persians later on
they use that with an ethnic
context uh so Afghanistan kind of has
that connotation the land of the ARA
people which is the old name of India
which is also the present day name of
Iran of Persia Iran Shah Iran kind of
means the land of the ARA people so
that's what Afghanistan that's what
Arana means it's been called by various
names the oldest is obviously gandhar
then you had what else was it called arq
osia the Greeks called it
aracosia uh and and various other names
as well aracosia comes from the word
Saraswati actually which the Greeks
probably didn't realize and and so on uh
and harana I'm not sure what that name
comes from but it's definitely not Rel
related to the Arana name of Afghanistan
so they're not really connected I am not
really sure what harana what the name
harana what the origin is that's an
interesting question I'm not sure but
I'm
pretty sure it's there's no connection
there between Arana and
harana another question by Imran naimi
most scientists and people don't accept
the evolution Evolution Theory theory of
evolution because they say it's a theory
not fact or hypothesis so how do most of
them accept the Big Bang Theory which is
also a theory I wouldn't agree that most
scientists don't accept evolution I
think if a scientist doesn't accept the
theory of evolution then that person is
in a very small minority and it's
because we have ample evidence of
evolution we know Evolution happened we
have the fossil record of this planet
that goes back about I don't know at
least a couple of billion years and we
can see I mean we know at what how do we
know a fossil is a certain age certain
date how old a fossil is so one way of
determining is determining this is to
see at what depth under the ground under
the Earth or at what
What sedimentary depth is it found so we
have sedimentary rocks if you go high up
in the Himalayas thousands of meters
above the sea level you'll find
sedimentary rocks with fossils sea sea
shells and fish fossilized in there so
that tells you that these mountains
emerged out of the oceans millions of
years ago about 50 or 60 million years
ago but by looking at the the sediments
and the the layers of St as estrata you
can tell how old a fossil is and you can
see that Evolution has happened based on
how fossilized life you can see the the
evolution of life in the fossils so
about
2.7 I think the oldest evidence of
microorganisms is about 3.7 billion
years before today and we find evidence
of fossil uh
microorganisms and and
uh and u based on their effects on rock
and all that and that tells you how old
that is so we we know that the oldest
evidence of life is unicellular life
then you have multicellular life
emerging and then you have uh complex
organisms emerging which is organisms
with which are multicellular and with
different organs and all that then you
have fish and and animals with shells
emerging at a different at a later time
so we know that there is a chronological
evolution in of and increasing
complexity in life on the planet and
when it comes to human beings we know
how the evolution has happened we know
that our ancestors I mean the oldest
Homo sapiens is about 400,000 years old
the oldest fossils are found in Northern
Africa jbel UD is the name of the cave
where they found the oldest archaic Homo
sapiens before that we had Homo erectus
and Homo habilis and Homo whatever else
and then before that we have the human
chimpanzee Divergence about four or four
billion four million years before today
before that about roughly 9 or 10
million years before today the ANC the
common ancestor of human humans and
chimpanzees diverged from the ancestor
of the gorillas and so on so we know the
entire process of evolution happened we
have uh evidence of that so I wouldn't
say that scientists don't accept
evolution as a theory it's not just a
theory it's a proven Theory and we have
evidence for it similarly when it comes
to the Big Bang Theory it it's all based
on
evidence uh so we have we know that the
best theory of uh gravitation that we
have is the general the theory of
relativity and we have evidence from the
cosmos about the oldest light in that we
know of which is the cosmic microwave
background radiation which is at a
temperature of about 2.7 Kelvin just
just barely above absolute zero we have
the evidence of all the stars galaxies
everything that's visible we know that
it's receding away from us because it's
red shifted so put all of that together
and you extra it backwards into time you
arrive at a big bang so once again it's
all based on evidence and logic and the
best theory of gravitation that we have
which is general relativity and the
standard model of cosmology the Lambda
CDM model all that so all these theories
are based on evidence that's how science
works so that's why evolution is the
best known Theory best theory that we
have for how life uh progressed over
over or chronological time periods and
similarly for the Big Bang which is the
the chronology of the universe
itself okay
okay okay kage says from Europe okay K
is in Europe looking at the map there's
no clear demarcation for Jammu and
Kashmir ladak solid lines on the map
show the country borders these
territories are shown with dotted lines
your thoughts look I am not in Europe I
am in India but I can show you the map
how it looks like if you open Google
Maps from India it will show you what
the government uh would like everybody
to see but if you see uh Google Maps
from outside of India you will see
dotted lines when it comes to Jammu and
Kashmir and ladak and it kind of
supports Pakistan's claims on Kashmir
and China's claims on whatever other
territories it will even show arunachal
Pradesh with a dotted line but even if
you are in India let me show you
something interesting okay let's let's
go to Google Maps we are in arunachal
Pradesh right now okay arunachal Pradesh
we're going to zoom in zoom into to the
Border region
okay and this is where does it say India
where does it say
Tibet it won't say anything here say
first of all it won't say whether it's
it's India one the southern part is
India and the northern part is allegedly
China but uh if you go
here then it may say India
Bangladesh okay maybe not even
here but but let me show you something
let's let's go back to arunachal Pradesh
and south of this line is India we know
that for sure now let me click just
south of the line what does it say it
says unavailable it doesn't say
arunachal Pradesh it doesn't say India
it says unavailable isn't that
interesting let's go let's say
here it says Tibet even though this is
Indian Territory see according to the
Google Map boundary itself the place I
clicked is within India you click there
it will say Tibet China let's click
here it says
unavailable what about some other place
let's let's let's find some other
place
um okay let's go north of taang let's go
here near the India Bhutan China trans
Tri Junction let's click here it'll say
unavailable okay let's click within
Bhutan okay it's not saying China it's
saying something else but in India if
you click it says unavailable now uh
let's go
here uh and I'm pretty sure this is also
India this is sikim right so let's go to
the northern part of sim and let's click
here it will say Tibet China when it is
clearly Indian Territory per Google Maps
itself now let's let's go to Nepal for
example the indiaan Nepal
border let's let's see that okay North
is Nepal of the Line south is India
let's see you click here it says Nepal
within Indian Territory it says
Nepal you see
that let's let's see some other place
let's go to over here the India Nepal
Tibet Tri
Junction okay let's click here what does
it say it says unavailable let's click
here once again unavailable
okay okay now let us go to lak let us
click here it will say unavailable
let us go near okay this
place and let's click here which is
within India it will say enari
prefecture Tibet
China so uh it's very clear that even if
you're in India even though it shows the
correct boundaries of India it's still
Google Maps still supports Chinese
claims on Indian Territory what
about
Pakistan okay let's go here okay within
po it will say Pakistan it will say kber
tuna Pakistan even though it shows that
as part of
India once again it shows this as part
of India we click here now it says
unavailable a different place let's see
here unavailable but one point that I
showed you just now it show it said
kber right okay let us go to this this
place
here it will say unavailable so you will
find that Google Maps
often not often frequently supports
Chinese claims of on Indian Territory
and often supports Pakistani claims of
on Indian Territory but it will it will
never show a non-indian territory as
Indian but it will often show Indian
Territory as either Pakistani or Chinese
okay and who who's the who's the person
running Google Mr Sundar picai Mr Sundar
picai right so that's what you get when
you have an Indian origin CEO in a
foreign company in an American company
an Indian celebrate Mr Sundar Pai and Mr
SAA nadala and whoever else being the
CEO of whatever alphabet and Microsoft
and whatnot what are you getting out of
it absolutely nothing yeah so these are
my thoughts about
it
okay okay DJ com says three days three
attacks in three days in Kashmir what's
your take is it a sign of terrorists
getting emboldened or is it a ploy like
Netanyahu allegedly to get back po we
need an excuse there is no getting back
po right
now okay there is no taking back P right
now po will come back when it comes to
comes back to us for that India has to
grow further India has to become a five
or ideally 10 trillion doll economy then
when once we are near that region near
that place P will automatically come
back to us we won't to fire a single
bullet and right now going to war is
madness it's Insanity we need peace in
India because with peace comes stability
and with stability comes economic growth
so please I don't know why people are so
obsessed with po no no PO this is not an
excuse It's not a ploy to take back po
so what's happening right now yeah the
terrorists are see the Pakistani see
where are these territ terrorists coming
from Pakistani terrorists yes our
favorite neighboring nation that Mr
Faruk Abdullah wants us to talk to again
he's saying we have to talk to them talk
with them we cannot resolve our problems
unless we speak speak with our neighbors
Hey listen there are ways of resolving
problems okay much nicer ways anyway so
these terrorists come from
Pakistan so it's not the terrorists who
are let's say getting emboldened it's
the pakistanis who are trying to push
their luck they they're trying to prod
India and see how far they can go and
how much they can get away with and
they're trying to tell send the world a
message that we have a weaker Indian
government in place I mean they're
trying to send that message and thus far
what have we done we've hunted down I
suppose the terrorists and and uh and uh
neutralized them the Army would have
done that hopefully all of them have
been neutralized but the pakistanis are
trying to kind of send a message to the
world that this government is weak this
Indian government is weak Mr Modi is not
the Modi of old Modi
2.0 maybe it's it's it's what they're
trying to do now the Pakistani
government is the Pakistani military and
they are controlled from outside they
are mercenaries so whoever is pulling
the strings is trying to have the
pakistanis send in terrorists to try and
create this impression now it all
depends
on what India does now how does India
respond to this so if it is a small
scale terrorist attack only like you
know every human life is precious but in
the context of geopolitics in human
lives are unfortunately regrettably
statistics so if it is like two three
people die in a small scale attack then
maybe we don't do anything about it we
just neutralize the terrorists and move
on but how far are we willing to let
this go on so three days three attacks I
mean that's not a good sign
so maybe we need to kind of push back
and take the fight to their Camp which
means across the P across the looc
perhaps it doesn't mean we take back po
it means we send a Stern message that
don't try your luck and I don't think
this President Modi government is weak
in that sense when it comes to National
Security so I think if the pakistanis
push too hard they're going to once
again face a nasty surprise like they
did in the
past mlen says why is everything so
Bland and boring nowadays meet
architecture car designs or clothing
everything is minimalist and low quality
you know you go back to the US uh movie
posters of the 1950s and 1960s they're
bright and
colorful if you look at the uh of if you
look at photographs in the US of the
1950s and 60s everything was bright and
colorful Billboards movie posters
uh the the paint on buildings the paint
on walls indoors everything the kind of
clothing people wore flower power 1950s
1960s Woodstock it was all bright
beautiful colorful and ever since it's
getting drabber and Grabber and blander
and blander and today everything is just
monochrome different Shades of Gray
architecture is ugly car designs are
minimalistic like you're saying clothing
is yeah
it tells you there's a decline in
Western Society if you look at it's not
just the visible stuff if you if you
read fiction today it's more dystopian
especially science fiction is all D
dystopian if you look at the movie
themes it's all nistic and and dystopian
things
themes uh yeah so overall that's the
mood in the west the West is in Decline
and maybe they're trying to engineer a
decline
so yeah that that's what it is I think
it's some of it is being engineered
overall the Western World Western
Society Western economy is is going you
know it's it's diminishing it's
declining there's inflation there is
recession there is an increasing sense
of of of Despair lack of Hope and in
such uh in such circumstances you cannot
expect there to be Beauty and vibrant
colors and all that so there's going to
be
the opposite of excess which is
minimalism and you're going to see a
decline in quality so it it has
something to do with with the state of
the economy uh and and the overall
trajectory of these Western powers in
the 195s 1960s it was like the UN the
the world war was there for the taking
they had won the second world war they
had encircled the USSR they were the
great the superior power they were
Superior Bally economically every in
everything and the economy was booming
so yeah so it was it was a time of great
optimism and you could see that
reflected in every manifestation of
culture and art and today it's the
opposite the West is declining they've
opened the doors the their borders for
certain kinds of
immigration only certain kinds of
immigration I mean if you want to
immigrate there legally they're going to
make you jump through hoops but if you
want to immigrate there illegally well
that's the easiest thing in the world
today so so overall it's it's not a good
time and art architecture culture
everything will reflect that attitude
and that mood that gloomy dark desperate
mood so that's what we are
seeing okay Richard says the Russian
submarines are deployed very close to
the US's coastal line and also on the in
the Cuban Waters do you think Russia
Russia is up to something big look the
Russians are saying if you can come
right to our doorstep and and fight a
proxy there if you can come and place
nuclear weapons almost in our backyard
then we are also capable of doing
something similar so if you remember
during President Kennedy's time the
Russians had placed nuclear missiles in
Cuba and that led to the Cuba Cuban
Missile Crisis which almost came to the
brink of uh nuclear Exchange
but SAR Minds prevailed and the crisis
was diffused so the US expect that a
great power like Russia a near superpow
like Russia should be completely fine
with them placing nuclear weapons and
and other kinds of offensive weapons
right in Russia's backyard and almost at
their doorstep but the Russians should
not come anywhere close to the US it
doesn't work like that so the Russians
have sent submarines of course they've
not placed missiles on Cuban Cuban soil
thus far
but they see it's something called
international waters so they every
nation has the right to send their ships
whether it's civilian ships or or or
military ships in international waters
so they're doing that and if if you can
if a friendly nation is willing to host
you then you can even send your military
vessels in the territorial Waters of the
friendly Nation so Russia and Cuba are
on good terms so there you have what's
happening so it's a message to the US
that if you can do this we can also do
that it's not a very well it's kind of a
strong message actually and uh they are
even going to do military exercises of
the of the West Coast of the US if
they've not done that already so the
Russians are also demonstrating their
their capabilities their Naval
capabilities their power projection
capabilities to some extent they're
showing it they're demonstrating it and
they are saying that we want back down
you can't bully us we can take action of
own so it's it's it's all kinds of
messaging going on right now but that
drives home the message that the
Russians are not a nation it's not a
nation that you can just push around
Russians can hit back and this is just a
reminder of that so I don't think the
Russians are up to anything big right
now anything big when it comes to us say
Russia is just war and we don't want war
because that war could end the world the
Russians are simply reminding the US
sending a message we also can do things
so take it easy back
off Malik's says how can one join the
Indian deep state does it even exist
well I would not know about it I don't
know if it exists uh what's the US deep
State first of all the term deep
State exists in the in in in the context
of the United States right deep state so
what is the US what is the alleged us
deep state so look at it this way today
you have a mentally handicapped
president in the US Joe Biden he
actually belongs in a retirement home he
is not all there right he's barely even
conscious and half the time he doesn't
know what he is saying so clearly he's
in no condition to take care of himself
right let Al let alone run an entire
nation and a superpower at that so Mr
Biden isn't running the US that's clear
any any person with half a brain can see
that now his Deputy the the vice
president is Miss Kamala Harris well
she's not the sharpest cookie on the
Block either so she's also not running
the US so who's running the United
States if it's not the president and the
vice president that's the big question
and clearly the nation is running itself
and it's not running itself on its own
somebody's running it and that is what
people would call the Deep state which
is the The Establishment The unelected
Establishment look Every Nation every
nation has certain
extra Democratic power centers power
centers that exist outside of the
democratic
process and the us obviously has that
they have an unelected power center that
is always in power which is the Pentagon
which is the defense establishment then
there's a foreign uh uh the Foreign
Service establishment then there is the
military industrial complex then there's
the Wall Street there's there are all
these cabals of oligarchs and un
unelected powerful people who kind of
determine the fortunes of the nation and
its people so that and the most powerful
Elites among these would be what we call
the Deep state so clearly clearly
there's some there is a deep state in
the US and there's obviously the Federal
Reserve which is a private bank that
essentially owns the us what a joke and
they call that that Nation a democracy
anyhow so there's a deep state in the US
that's very clear do we have one in
India so to have something like that in
India would mean that the Indian Prime
Minister and the Council of ministers
are not really running the nation but
there's something deeper behind that's
actually controlling the nation I don't
think that's quite the
case okay so I don't think something
like that exists in India obviously
there there's going to be power centers
that are extra Democratic you know old
money money people with money that dates
back to the British
times which means that their ancestors
were collaborators of the British they
served British interests over Indian
interests and they made a lot of money
in the process and their descendants who
who exist today still have that money so
those people will have power as well to
to some extent especially when you
network that's how you create power
right and then there are certain
political parties that that date back to
the pre to the pre pre pre-independence
pre4 47 era and so on so certain such
things do exist in India but I would not
call it a deep State as such the kind of
deep state that you most likely have in
the US so if you want to join that
you you have to either Join one of those
political parties or or or or become
very wealthy and Ally yourself with
those people with old money or something
like that I guess that's what I would
say all
right okay um
okay let's see this chirag ATI says if
World War II occurs and major Nations
like the US Russia and China destroy
each other while India remains neutral
will India emerge as a superpower
similar to the USA after World War II
that is a great question first of all if
World War III happens it won't be
between the US and China it will be a
war between the US and Russia China is
not even in the picture when it comes to
the two most powerful nations in the
world China is the second largest
economy in the world but when it comes
to hard power hard power China is
leagues behind
Russia
Russia is about is is very close in in
in power hard power to the US and
primarily because of its gigantic
nuclear weapons Arsenal so a World War I
would only be a war between the US and
Russia and maybe the Chinese would alive
with Russia if if this if they wish to
okay it depends on the number of factors
so let's say This World War
III and these nations destroy each other
okay let's say China is also involved so
it's it's the US versus Russia and China
let's
say and in such a scenario I think all
three nations will get smashed up
there's going to
be assuming this nuclear exchange that
would mean that almost nothing survives
it means that the US is like 80 90% gone
so is Russia is China now here's the
deal if that happens and India remains
neutral India will remain neutral in
this so if India remains neutral will
India emerge as a superpower similar to
the US after the second world war that
is the question and I my answer
regrettably is no it won't remain a
superpower and uh let me explain why
India won't remain a superpower or even
if the US and Russia and China uh get
destroyed okay one second so let me put
something on the screen so first of all
understand that if there's a nuclear
exchange there's going to be complete
Devastation in the world now look at
this so the
US has the United States they have
something called the single integrated
operational plan this
siop okay now this is is a a classified
thing it's a guarded secret but it's
been around since the days of Kennedy
and it's kind of known what this is so
the
siop is what they do if they go to
nuclear war and it's preme premised on
the notion that America would be the
largest surviving civilization if
there's a nuclear exchange but to
guarantee that America Remains the
largest surviving civilization we have
to kill everybody in the
world so most presidents would say that
is that is
madness we need a different uh option
but they typically don't get other
options
so
uh so the Pentagon always gives them
options that inevitably lead to that
scenario where the Americans have to
kill
everyone uh so George Bush brought this
back again and so
on
uh so what this means is that we going
to blow up we means the Americans we're
going to blow up go up the entire world
because we know that in a post nuclear
environment we can't allow for instance
India to survive intact if we are
reduced to 30% of our capab capacity we
can't allow India to have a superior
civilization in a post nuclear conflict
we're going to destroy India we're going
to destroy the whole world that's what
the American nuclear war plan is okay
and it's on automatic status so it will
happen automatically once the red button
is pressed it will it will all be
programmed and it will just happen on
its own nobody will then be able to stop
it or or change the sequence of Nations
that are destroyed and so on it's going
to happen on
automatic so if there's a third world
war if the
US starts or is part of a nuclear
exchange with anyone then a sequence of
events is already pre-programmed in that
red button which involves destroying
India so forget about emerging is a
superpower my friends India won't
exist if there's a nuclear war between
the US and Russia or between us and
China or between the US and Russia plus
China even though India has nothing to
do with this they will destroy
India interesting and it's not
hypothetical if War happens they will do
it they will destroy India so what
should India do about
this what should India do about this
if War happen if nuclear war happens
which doesn't involve India we are
guaranteed to be destroyed they will
make sure of it so what should India do
India will cease to
exist I would say that India should
increase its stockpile of nuclear
weapons to at least a
thousand and make and and send them the
message that you destroy us you won't
survive
either that's what I would say it's it's
a ghastly horrible hideous scenario but
that's what these people are capable
of and they teach us human rights and
democracy and freedom and values and
whatnot so I think India should also be
prepared that if somebody wants to
annihilate us they won't survive intact
this is unfortunately the consequence of
their kind of
thinking we we we we did not come up
with this plan right but we have to
respond in some way so I think India
needs to increase its nuclear weapon
stockpile to maybe at least a thousand
which will serve other purposes also of
course but yeah if if somebody wants to
just destroy us for no reason there's no
need for the allowing no need to allow
them to survive either so yeah good
question that you've asked me and it's
absolutely ghastly that this sort of
thinking exists in the
world okay ratees raat says what is
what's your rating of Peter the Great on
a scale of 1 to 10
how come no one thought of westernizing
modernizing and expanding Russia before
him your take on his taxation on beards
and P Patriarchs so this guy was a
member of the Romanov Dynasty I remember
somebody had asked me a question about
Peter the Great last time anyhow I'm
glad this is a more specific question so
how do I rate him from on a scale of 1
to 10 I would say that he's probably
seven or eight a very great man they
call him Peter the Great he dragged
Russia out of
out of uh agrarian cultivation status
into a modern you know into a Modern
Nation it was an agrarian Nation it was
a very backward Nation no technology
nothing of any nothing nothing to write
home about and he made Russia into a
Modern Nation he tried to make Russia
European didn't quite succeed but yeah
he made he turned Russia into a great
power so Peter the Great uh I forget the
name of his father but Peter the Great
had two siblings at least two siblings a
brother and a sister I think the sister
was older if I'm not mistaken and uh she
was the Regent in the Kingdom for a
while uh after the father died I believe
and she was kind of power hungry she did
a good job of ruling the
country and then uh she was power hungry
she tried to grab power and she was
banished to a monastery and she had to
become a nun and then these these two
brothers ruled for a while and then
Peter's brother dies so Peter becomes
the only
ruler and Peter was a impressive guy 7
feet tall I think he
was and he was fond of traveling he
spent a lot of time in Western Europe in
the West in the UK and other places he
was impressed by their technology their
ship building capabilities technology
and all that he imported that in Russia
and he turned Russia into a ship
building nation and brought in other
technology as well and uh he outlawed
beards that's kind of Weir until until
he was until he came to power every
Russian male typically would have a
beard and he outlawed beards and there
was a lot of uh push back against that
and then eventually he said okay you can
have beards but you to pay a tax so
there was a beard tax you want to keep a
you had to pay a tax and there were some
changes in the church as well whether do
you do the sign of the cross with two
fingers or three fingers or some
nonsense like that and some some church
people burn themselves to death over the
small change and people are people you
know dogmatic and all that whatever and
uh what else did he do uh so he he made
Russia into a Modern Nation he fought
Wars with lots of people Sweden I
believe Sweden was there Poland was
there and all uh you have to look up the
chronology
uh and
uh and he had a son I forget the son's
name also but the son was kind of uh um
he was influenced by people who were
against Peter the Great and he grew up
to hate his father and his father wanted
him to carry on the work but he kind of
refused and he TR and I believe he
defected to another country Austria or
something which was great humiliation
for Peter so he somehow got the sun back
and
then I guess the son was beaten by was
put thrown into jail and beaten by his
captives which are Peter's Peter's
minions and the Sun dies and eventually
I think one of his daughters succeeded
him long term I he had another son also
who died in his
teens so
yeah the taxation on beard was weird but
he is the man who made Russia a modern
power so very strange personal life he
got his own son killed and he ended up
with with no
male descendants male hairs uh but
overall he was he was a great uh great
reformer in
Russia and uh yeah so on a scale of 1 to
10 I would give him a seven or a eight
overall but yeah I mean some of the
things he did were crazy kind of on the
same lines as Ivan the Terrible kind of
yeah
okay
uh okay geopolitical dub says government
decides to change some name area names
in Tibet will we see has the government
done
that has the government of India renamed
some parts of Tibet really I'm not sure
about that okay maybe I'm not seen but I
would be very surprised if that is the
case will we see India's wolf Warrior
policy in PM modi's thirdd term uh look
I don't expect wolf Warrior diplomacy
from India at PM modi's F thirdd term
what I expect is status quo keep on re
keep on growing the economy and keep on
following the same foreign policy the
same Pakistan policy Mr modi's Pakistan
policy is great just ignore them and
isolate them from our perspective
foreign policy is good be friends with
everybody and have win-win cooperation
with everybody grow the economy economic
policy overall good infrastructure
development all that good so I just want
more of that I expect nothing else I
don't expect Mr Modi to reform any the
education system or do anything about
culture civilization I don't have any
any such expectations just keep doing
more of the same I don't see any wolf
Warrior diplomacy coming up I don't
think it's even desirable at this moment
in time when you are this much of a
Nation you are India is the world's
fourth most powerful
Nation okay it is from the perspective
of hard power but it is a third as
powerful as China almost the fourth as
powerful which means China is about four
times more powerful than
India and Russia is about three or four
times more powerful than China the US is
twice as powerful as Russia so India is
way way way down even though it's the
fourth most powerful Nation so I think
India should not try and act bigger than
its size India should keep its head down
and just focus on economic growth I
don't want wol Warrior diplomacy I don't
want talk about visha Guru and
superpower okay what Vish Guru your your
education system is garbage how can you
be a guru with a garbage education
system all this I don't know what neat
and stuff whatever is
happening that nonsense with with the
neat the medical entrance exam thing so
listen don't talk about being visha Guru
don't talk about being super power just
just focus on the fundamentals the next
20 years then we then we'll think about
talking about other things so that's
what I would
say UB says I've seen some so-called
Tibetan origin geopolitical experts
saying that arunachal Pradesh is a part
of Southern Tibet Taiwanese Chinese
Tibetans all of them claiming arunachal
Pradesh please explain
look there are some Tibetan uh experts
academics or whatever even there are
even some monks or whatever who are
outside of Chinese occupied Tibet some
of them may be in the west some of them
may perhaps be in India perhaps I'm not
sure and some and some of these people
could possibly POS be on the Chinese
payroll okay for whatever reason I don't
know what reason some of it may be under
duress because they may have family in
Tibet some of it may simply be because
they've been paid by the Chinese some of
it may be because they've been
brainwashed whatever it is I don't care
but there are going to be people of
Tibetan origin who
actually are what JK Rowling would call
blood Traders you know if you read Harry
Potter blood blood Traders so there are
going to be such Tibetan individuals who
will work to further the Chinese cause
and betray their own people and
obviously furthering the Chinese cause
means to say things that are anti-india
as well that also is part of being
pro-china so I'm not saying all Tibetans
are like this most Tibetans are really
nice people and they really would want
to go back to a free Tibet one day but
some Tibetans uh are on the Chinese
payroll for whatever reason and such
people will make such claims there are
even such people some such people a few
sprinkling of such people in Bhutan as
well okay who actually uh Echo the
Chinese
refrain
so we need to be aware that such people
exist and don't let their nonsense
affect you okay that's it let them say
whatever they want be aware that these
people sing the Chinese Tunes that's it
nothing else there's nothing more to
explain about it okay Tibet itself isn't
part of of China I do not recognize
Tibet as part of China Tibet is Chinese
occupied Tibet it is not China and one
day Tibet will be
free and we're going to ensure that
someday India will ensure this not this
current government maybe in the next 20
30 years it will happen but Tibet will
be free again free of China free of
Chinese occupation so that's what I can
say there's nothing more to explain
about this
uh all
right anamica says nowadays there's a
lot of cases of question paper leaks
occurring even in an exam like NE the
paper got leaked in various places what
measures should the government
take look what does this mean it means
there is corruption right if an exam
paper gets leaked what does it mean it
means there is corruption and if there
is corruption where is the corruption
it's in the education system and the
infrastructure that surrounds the
education system the bureaucrats and the
officials and all who are in charge of
these things and so on some there is
some corruption somewhere in there I'm
not saying I'm not specifically pointing
fingers at person X or person y or
person Zed or organization this or that
I'm saying somewhere in there there is
corruption and overall I'll explain to
you I I'll I'll tell you I'll assure you
that the education system is rotten it
is garbage and with a rotten and garbage
education system you can have no future
in your country and what frustrates me
no end is that the Modi government had
10 years to make some changes and they
came up with nothing okay it frustrates
me no end I was I was hoping that in 10
years something will start what's that
movie I forget the name of the movie in
whichi says
that
system right the government may be
theirs but the system is ours so the
Modi government had 10 years to start
reforming the system the education
system which is the core of the future
of India but they did nothing they've
come up with some new education policy
which is garbage which is going to
change nothing it doesn't address any of
the fundamental issues it is like
putting putting U it is like putting
lipstick on an Egyptian
mummy
okay so it's absolute it does nothing so
what measures should the government take
you cannot take any short-term measures
for this you have to reform the entire
education system from bottom up it's a
fundamental systemic change that you
need it takes time it will take 20 years
if you start today which is why I was
hoping that Mr Modi when he came to
power in 2014 he would have started
something but no no no no we're going to
continue the same so we're going to keep
on working but we won't change the
system which means that every is officer
who comes out every year every year
there's a bunch of high officers who who
come who who pass the whatever exam it
is that they have
and what happens they go through the
entire process of of indoctrination and
brainwashing and uh you see what happens
then and forget about IAS officers every
single student who goes to the education
system ends up alienated deracinated and
many of them end up being Hindu phobic
hitting their own culture so this should
have been
reformed this system should have been
reformed at least something should have
been done the new education policy
doesn't do anything of doesn't address
any of the core issues okay you've
changed some chapters here and there you
added a few paragraphs or something what
does it what difference does it make you
have to reform the system at the core
and I'm not going to go into how to do
it I've got three live streams ask 38 39
40 or somewhere around that in three
live streams which have gone into great
depth about what needs to be done those
are the measures the government should
have taken they still can take it but I
have no hope because if they could not
do anything in 10 years what will they
do in 5 years so I don't know it's it's
extremely disappointing but that's where
we are I all I hope is that they keep on
uh they
keep they they continue the the policies
when it comes to the economy the
infrastructure foreign policy defense
all of that maybe a more robust defense
policy hopefully but yeah I have no
other hopes from this government but
still I would say it's still the best
government that we have because there is
no
alternative it's still the best
government we could have asked for as of
today
2024 uh but yeah it's extremely
disappointing that the these things
happen there is corruption at various
levels in the education system students
who study so hard they don't get what
they studied for and people and and
students who had not studied that well
actually are able to Le frog over the
ones who are actually meritorious and
then then there's the question of
reservations reservations are so it's
it's so unfair it's so unfair UC ation
should be all about
Merit but yeah India is not is in a
nation in which Merit doesn't
really it's not recognized so yeah I
mean we we still have so so long such a
long way to go India and yeah the
ne leak extremely unfortunate I I can
imagine how those students are feeling
trust me I have also seen some of that
in my own time so I know exactly how it
is yeah
what measures the government take yeah I
wonder
what
okay okay YouTube laughter says how to
become an independent geopolitical
expert and how to manage it with my
college studies I'm an IT student
because if you have started Living
learning history and geopolitics kindly
help look if you want to take up a
career in something that career
should give you an income that is
sufficient to
sustain your lifestyle and your family's
lifestyle it could be a most luxurious
lifestyle living in palaces or it can be
a modest lifestyle whatever it is
lifestyle could be anything but it
should be able to sustain you and your
family give you a proper
income now there is no industry in India
or the us called the geopolitics
industry which produces some Goods every
year so there's no huge demand in
society for geopolitical
experts so if you're going to be a
geopolitical let me just give you the
the truth the
reality if you're going to be a
geopolitical expert it's going to be a
hobby it's not going to be a full-time
career unless you are hired by some
think tank or something and there how
many think tanks do we have in India a
handful
and uh and they would look for certain
criteria you would need to have a
master's degree or something in
international relations you may be they
may want a PhD also in that or or in an
Allied topic like political science or
history or
something uh so that's what they would
need and if you are in one of these T
tanks you get employment there then you
may get a decent salary
okay but and and to be a geopolitical
expert like you're saying
uh an geopolitical
expert you become an expert after decade
or two of studying of really really
really researching
history okay you don't become a
geopolitical expert at the age of 18 or
25 or
30 maybe 30 you can call yourself a
geopolitical analyst it's a long process
so let me just give you a dose of
reality because I know you
may not understand the full picture so
it's good I'm I'm glad that you're
interested in history and
geopolitics but to be an expert is a
long long journey and you want get
employment in a think tank without at
least a master's degree in international
relations or a PhD in something like
that so that's what I would say I would
say that take first you know you have to
be realistic and practical in life first
get your finances sorted you need to
have a steady source of income uh
especially if you are from from like
most Indians are from middle class
background you need to be very careful
about that most of most Indians don't
have a huge bank balance their parents
struggled just your parents would have
struggled if you an ordinary Indian to
just give you an education so make sure
that you have a
good um income first of all and then you
can keep on studying in the on the side
Di and eventually by the 30 or whatever
you could perhaps become an Act
geopolitical expert maybe start your own
Think Tank and do work for various
government agencies or whatever or
something like that or maybe you can get
employment somewhere in the think tank
so that's how it is there is no actual
career in India called geopolitical
expert how many do we have how many some
people who work for think tanks are
geopolitical experts and some people on
their own one or two maybe geopolitical
experts but apart from that there's not
much more okay so it's not it may look
glamorous and all that but it's
extremely hard I'm just telling you the
truth I don't want you to end up in a
dead dead alley okay you know when
you're running from the cops when you're
a robber running from the cops and you
go into a street and suddenly there's a
wall in front of you where do you go you
don't want to be there so yeah that's
what I would say
uh Brian Lord says doing bachelor's
degree in Germany computer scien as
middle class student education loan I
don't know what the question
is ideally you don't want to take a loan
it's fine to do a degree outside of
India because India's education
education system is terrible it's
garbage it's ghastly so okay you want to
go abroad and get a degree all right
good ideally you want to get a
scholarship which means that you don't
need Al
loone okay but very few people get
scholarships you need to whatever exam
what GRE and toffle and all that you
need to get a tremendously good score
and then you have to apply for a
scholarship most American universities
and colleges would give scholarships to
those who are the most deserving only a
few will get scholarships so ideally you
want to get a tremendously good score in
whatever exam you're going to pass sat
GRE tofel blah blah blah what what else
do we have whatever else do we have we
have I don't remember so you get that
then you will get a Admissions Office of
ADM admission plus scholarship if you
don't get a scholarship then I guess you
will have to ask your parents to take a
loan from A bank and they're going to
have to fund you through that so yeah
that's another option but that's harder
for your parents obviously and for you
as well in case it's your money you're
using otherwise your parents so yeah
that's what I
say
okay uh we
vishak
vishaka vishaka kabila sorry I'm sorry I
couldn't read properly vishaka kabila
says why are so many bangladeshis and
Africans living in Southern India okay I
don't know about Southern
India I don't know about Africans but
when it comes to Bangladesh is they are
all over
India why are they all over India well
they typically generally pour in through
the almost open borders in eastern
India which part of Eastern India you
say well let's take a look at the map
the map is our best friend okay where is
map is here let's see map so if
Bangladesh is are pouring into India
where would they pour in from I'm I'm
just guessing from the map okay don't
blame me for the answers blame the map
so if they want to come to let's say
Southern India Western India Northern
India what's the best most best way it's
to come east sorry westwards from
Bangladesh right westwards so what is
west of
Bangladesh well west of Bangladesh you
have West Bengal you have Bihar I guess
and east of Bangladesh you have tripura
megala and as northern part you have
Assam and so on so that's where they
would generally pour in from and it's a
very porous almost open border I'm I'm
told and the wonderful BSF border
security force is in charge of guarding
the borders and uh
well I'll just uh say go and search the
news about BSF and Bangladesh border
that's all I will say I will say no more
than
that so the bangladeshis are just
pouring into
India they have been doing that for the
past few decades and I remember in 2014
it was
said that about 50 million bangladeshis
were in India in 2014 which is about a
decade
ago so in 10 years how many more would
have poured into India I don't know I
guess your guess is as good as mine but
let's say you got another 10 20 million
coming into India so maybe we have now
70 million or so Bangladesh is in India
so I don't know about Africans but
Bangladesh is it's very clear that we
don't have any border
security uh whatever measures we have
are not working why are they not working
I think we should ask the government not
me
okay because it's the job of the
government to ensure that this happens
and the question is what has been done
about the Bangladesh is who are in
inside India how many of them have been
repatriated have been expelled out of
India and sent back to
Bangladesh how many in the past 10 years
how many have been sent
back I wonder how many so that's why
there are so many Bangladesh is in India
and once they come into India they get
immediately AAR cards that's what one
hears allegedly
they allegedly get AAR cards once you
have an AAR card you can get all other
documents and once you have documents
you become an Indian Citizen and once
you have those documents nobody can send
you out and you will see in all these
towns and cities and Villages across
India all these bangladeshis my problem
is not with the Africans there may be a
few here that's okay the problem is with
the
bangladeshis because they are in here in
India in such incredible large numbers
and nothing is being done to address the
issue so we grow the economy we become a
10 trillion doll economy the Bangladesh
is by the time they have multiplied to
from 70 million to 140 million and they
inherit all the economic
growth and they outbreed the Indians
that's what will happen so what's being
done about this threat this demographic
threat it's a separate nation right
so they should be in their Nation not
here uh that's that's what I can say I
don't know why it's like this why I
don't know why the government is doing
nothing about this this is one of my
other big disappointments with with the
Modi
government when Mr Modi was campaigning
in 2014 for the El for the prime
ministri election he had been announced
as the prime ministri candidate I
remember he had gone to a rally in Assam
and he had said that all the illegal
Bangladesh is borea band because once I
become Prime Minister you'll be out well
it's been 10 Years sir 10
years how many Bangladesh's have gone
out you had made that promise right what
happened so yeah what can I
say okay let's see some other
questions uh unknown says why did it
take so long to start making the a MCA
aircraft look aircraft making is a long
process especially when it comes to
fighter aircraft which are very
complicated machines so we had the Tes F
program that began in the what
1980s and we now have actual fighter
planes in significant numbers in the Air
Force and we are still improving the Tes
aircraft you the Tes mark one then the T
just Mark 1 a with significant
improvements over the Mark 1 then
there's going to be a mark 2 which is
going to have even more improvements or
the Mark 1 a so even when you have an
aircraft that's in service you still
keep improving that and whatever lessons
you learn from that you can apply that
in other aircraft families now the AMC
Advanced medium combat aircraft is a
whole different category of fighter it's
not a light combat aircraft like the
thees it's a medium combat aircraft and
the amca if I not mistaken will have two
engines instead of a single engine which
like the thees
has if I'm not mistaken AMC probably has
two
engines let me just Google it
amca
amca uh let's see what it looks
like one second does it have a single
engine does it have two
engines so yes it looks like it's a twin
engine fighter plane with uh two back
nozzles for the
exhaust uh so yes it's a twin engine
fighter plane with two intakes and two
exhausts as you can see yeah okay so
that's the point so why does it take so
long so right now we are in the design
phase I think designs are kind of
finalized then you will have a couple of
prototypes that that are made one will
be used for taxiing on the runway once
that works out fine the other one
probably the second or the third
prototype will actually take flight it's
a long process because we don't want to
run into any big hurdles or any big
problems we do step bystep iterative
improvements and test various systems
and subsystems one by one when all the
ground systems are tested then you can
try a flight before you you fly it you
put it in a wind tunnel and see the
aerodynamics and the shape and all that
uh so it's a long process and many of
the learnings of the Tes program will be
implemented in the amca program so I
believe the first flight will happen in
the late 2020s and the first uh
production models maybe in the early
2030s that's how long it takes uh when
it comes to any fighter plane whether
it's the Rafal whether it's the F35
whether it's the F22 Raptor whether it
is the various suco fight planes or
whatever it's It generally takes 20 or
so years even the yeah so and we here
also there are missed opportunities so
India had a tremendously good fighter
plane the marut in the 1960s and70s the
marut the only problem is that it had an
underpowered engine there was nothing
wrong with the plane it was a brilliant
fighter plane designed by a
German uh
engineer Kurt tank but it had
underpowered engines so if he if we had
procured high high quality engines the
marut was would have would have been one
of the best fighter plays in the world
but the government of India killed the
marut program
because because there are incentives to
buy from abroad from and if you do that
you get you get some percentage to keep
in your pocket
allegedly so marut program was killed if
the program had not been killed by now
we would have had fifth generation
fighter planes because we would have
iteratively improved on the Maru and you
would have spinoff families of fighter
planes based on that well proven well
tested model so it didn't happen then we
started again from zero with the LCA Tes
it took about I don't know what 30 35 40
years to develop and now the amca will
take about 105 years so it it usually
takes time when it comes to fight
L
okay all right what else do we have
um ratish raat says hypothetically if
Wilders become became the eu's highest
positioned leader how would that change
the world compared to the EU we have and
we had till now it would do it would
make no difference no difference
whatsoever why do I say that it's
because the U EU is not a sovereign
organization it's not a sovereign body
it is entirely controlled by the
US there's nothing in the EU
documentation that says that we will be
controlled by the
us but that's still how it is so when it
comes to the EU Every Nation that's a
part of the EU has to go through certain
hoops and jumps and all those things and
reform itself before it is worthy of
being part of the EU and uh all of that
is mandated in the what is it called
membership something program membership
accession program and all that and when
you become a member of the EU you kind
of lose some of your sovereignty because
there is spooled sovereignty and many of
the EU nations are also NATO Nations
NATO member states which again all that
so overall if you look at the EU it's a
highly bureaucratic organization it it
takes away sovereignty from its Nation
St its member nation states and it is
essentially controlled by the us so it
doesn't matter who becomes the highest
the EU president or whatever it makes no
difference overall just like it makes no
difference whether Mr Trump or Mr uh
Biden or Miss Kamala Harris or Mr
Kennedy or whoever is in power as the US
president it makes no difference US
policy doesn't change internally there
may be some changes but foreign policy
doesn't change and uh regime change
policy doesn't
change so similarly when it comes to the
EU it doesn't matter who's the leader
won't make any significant change at
all all
right 2K Watts photography says should
India work on trust vectoring technology
for its AMC a fifth generation fighter
what are some of the benefits of the
thrust vectoring engines and how useful
is it in potential combat scenario trust
vectoring engines are engines in which
the nozzle
can change its angle which means that uh
that you can change the angle of the
exhaust jet in different
orientations in a way that a regular jet
engine can't and that allows the fighter
plane to do extremely extremely
difficult Maneuvers like the pugachev
Cobra that a regular fighter plane can't
so let's let's find out what a Thrust
vectoring engine is like thrust vect in
so let me put that on screen yes what do
I mean by thrust
vectoring so as you can see this is an
example of thrust vectoring there you
have it you can see that the the jet
engine is just straight but its nozzle
can change the direction of the of the
Jet and that allows hyper
maneuverability in a fighter plane so
once again over here you can see that
both the these are the exhausts of sukko
57 you can see it can they can change
their orientation so that can allow the
fighter plane to do extremely uh
difficult Maneuvers like the pugachev
Cobra I believe this is this is a
pugachev cobra maneuver one second J10
this is Chinese thing so if you want to
see so that's again another example of a
Thrust vectoring engine now let me show
you what the pugachev Cobra is
pugachev
kubra so that's this essentially is the
pugachev Cobra it's an it's an insanely
ridiculously difficult maneuver that you
can't do without a Thrust vectoring
engine so this is a plane doing the the
pugach of
Cobra and yeah so so that's what thrust
vectoring is and it gives you gives your
fighter plane extreme maneuverability
and uh that's good you always want every
Advantage you can possibly have so yeah
it would be great if India could acquire
thrust vectoring technology the puko 30
mki I think has thrust vectoring
engines um when it comes to the the amca
fifth generation fighter I think India
should have eventually its own jet
engine I believe we are we are working
with the French as well as the Russians
when it comes to jet engine technology
maybe we'll have two families of jet
engines if everything goes well and
hopefully we will have thrust vectoring
technology in those engines even if we
don't have thrust vectoring as long as
we have an indigenous engine that whose
technology we own whether we have bought
it from elsewhere or not doesn't matter
it should be something we can produce
inhouse then we're good and then we can
work on thrust vectoring capabilities
and all that later on but yes ideally
you would want to have that capability
that technology because it's great it
gives you advantages over non thrust
vector
engines Dr J Shankar says do you see the
rise of right-wing parties in Europe as
a threat to India's Global Ambitions or
will it help our nation considering
their history okay so the question is
what are India's Global
Ambitions we don't have Global Ambitions
right
now okay we are not I don't
want to see India as a visha guru right
now with a third rate education system
you can't be a Vish Guru
and we not even beginning to re to
reform the education system so first of
all Global Ambitions in visha Guru no no
Vish Guru we are right now a visha
student all right so no Global Ambitions
when it comes to that visha Guru what
else
superpower by first become a regional
power we are kind of becoming a regional
power superpow don't even think about a
being a superpow until 2050 then we can
start perhaps Whispering about it not
even speaking aloud but today Indians
are all super power super power Vish
Guru Vish Guru we don't have Global
Ambitions right now you can't Sprint
like you say in Bolt if you don't even
know how to
walk so first learn how to walk then
learn how to jog then learn how to run
then learn how to do a 400 MERS and then
learn how to sprint like you in
Bol step by step so so I would say first
of all we don't have global Ambitions we
want to be friends with everybody we
matter now in the Indian Ocean region we
matter in Asia from the American
perspective we are a good counterbalance
to China but they have a counterbalance
to India also which is Pakistan a
nuclear powered State and that's a US
sto so it's all Checkmate Checkmate
everywhere that's the balance of power
the Americans have created so from their
perspective India has limited utility
only as a counterbalance to China
nothing else and they don't want to see
India rise much further so our challenge
is to grow economically steadily for the
next 20 years minimum steady consistent
economic growth 6 7 8% if you can do
more than that great I I won't complain
but minimum
6% keep doing that until what until 2050
yeah and don't go to war with anybody
until then make sure there's no war
somehow the other avert
War so that's what India needs to do
when it comes to right-wing part parties
in the US in in Europe great we'll be
friends with them if there are lewi
parties in Europe great we will be
friends with them we will be friends
with everybody we are Vish friend we
have to be Vish Mitra not visha Guru not
visha power or whatever we want to have
win-win relations with everybody that's
where we want to be right now so if it
is Barack Obama we're going to be
friends with him if it's Trump we're
going to be friends with him if it is
Biden we'll be friends with him
if it is uh Senor senorina milone Madame
milone will be friends with her if it is
M makong who the left we friend with
we'll be friends with him whoever it is
we will be friends with them as long as
it serves a mutually beneficial purpose
so it makes no difference to us it's not
any threat to India right-wing part is
actually I would say if they genuinely
rightwing parties in Europe they would
actually be more favorably inclined
disposed towards India but if you have
an
astute leader like Mr Modi he is able to
establish good relations with just about
anybody he is great he has a great
personal connection with M makong of
France he has a great personal
connection with Madame milone of Italy
they are Polar Opposites Madame milone
is right Mr M M is left Mr Modi has
great relations with all the leaders
that matter in West as
Mr Netanyahu Mr Muhammad bin Salman and
so
on
so if you want to do it you can do it so
I don't see that as a concern the rise
of left wing or right wing or whatever
part is in Europe it makes no difference
to us they have their national interests
we have our national interests wherever
there is Convergence we'll work together
and it won't matter if they're left or
right we'll still be
friends Arijit banerji says has China
occupied 2 th000 square kilm of Indian
Land since 2020 after the galwan
Skirmish as stated by many Western and
Indian media outlets look I have seen no
evidence of that people will make claims
and claims have uh have purposes agenda
I have been I have been to the
Lac of course I haven't been to the
entire Lac the 2,000 kilometers of it
but I have been to parts of the LA I
don't see any such thing of course being
to a couple of points of the LA doesn't
make any thing but I have not seen any
such thing on the satellite images as
well we can go to Google Maps and see a
reasonably recent image and you can see
that the borders are kind of where they
are the LSC is kind of where it is and
you can actually pay for satellite
images which are like today satellite
images and you will also see even then
that there's no 2,000 square square
kilometers the that's gone the LC is
fluid okay and we have not the since
since 1962 our governments have not
developed any border infrastructure Mr
Modi has been doing that at break neck
speed since 2014 but we are still
catching up with China so the Chinese
will try and push on the advantage and
there may be some encroachment here and
there but it's not going to be 2,000
square kilometers so I don't believe it
maybe there is something here or there
perhaps possibly I don't know I have not
seen but we have to be open to the
possibility that maybe some some bits
and pieces they may have bitten off
somewhere or the
other but we are trying to catch up it's
not Mr modi's fault he has been doing
everything he can since 2014 to address
this to redress this situation so I
don't believe that India has lost 2,000
square kilometers of land I don't
believe that I have seen no evidence of
that so that's my perspective you can
believe or not believe that's entirely
up to you but you should be you should
get convincing convincing evidence of
what of if somebody makes a
claim okay
lus says I'm about to complete my
master's degree in chemical engineering
from TU Del I'm not sure what that is
but okay let's see what Tu Del
is let's erase the pugachev cobra in Tu
Del what is T
Del is
where ah is Netherlands okay so you're
doing your Masters in chemical
engineering from the Netherlands
chemical engineering I'm excited to
start working but I'm scared of getting
into a wrong stter job how do I approach
this the way to approach this is to be
very very well prepared and very very
well researched what are all the
possible job opportunities that you can
get what industries can you work in
where are these opportunities available
how much do they pay what's the
long-term uh uh prospects if you are in
this job or that job there are so many
websites that give you all these details
you have to intensively research and be
completely well informed and completely
prepared don't go into this with your
eyes Clos or half half open do as much
research as possible spend days and
nights doing the research prepare Excel
sheets with as much data as possible
once you are completely well prepared I
don't think it's it's uh likely that you
will make any mistakes so I understand
you scared you know what scares us
Darkness scares us what is Darkness
Darkness is simply the absence of
data okay that's why humans are scared
of
Darkness because darkness is the absence
of Light which means we don't get any
signal electromagnetic signal which
means there's no data and because I am
let's say I'm in this room and the
lights go off there's going to be a
momentary instinctive reaction of fear
oh my God all Darkness I know everything
that's in this room but still that that
instinctive reaction comes out and then
you're like hey relax I know this is my
room there's nothing unseen here that
has emerged after it went dark that sort
of thing thing my point is Darkness
scares us because it's the absence of
data you need to do as much research as
possible research all job opportunities
everything that's available create Excel
sheets create charts create create
graphs whatever you want look at the job
prospects you take this job what are
prospects like what is the career
trajectory like in the next five years
10 years do all your research all your
due diligence and when you are fully
equipped with all the data you will find
there's nothing to fear of course
there's always going to be some
uncertainty but the probability of that
uncertainty is less so that's what I
would
say that's how you approach it by being
well prepared rigorously well
prepared chirag says would India have
been better off under French rule
instead of British rule or would it not
have made any difference also with the
French or Romans more cruel is colonial
Powers look I would say if you were to
compare the French and the British with
the with the Romans
I would say perhaps the Romans were less
cruel and less
destructive for example the Romans uh
they conquered
Greece Julius Caesar conquered Greece
and that's where Greece loses its
sovereignty it has never regained its
sovereignty since then over 2,000 years
ago this happened and since then Greece
has never been what it used to be so so
the Romans colonized conquered Greece
colonized Greece but they never
destroyed Greek
culture so the Greeks became Roman
subjects but Rome actually absorbed much
of Greece's
culture and made it its
own so Greece did not
suffer uh cultural Devastation cultural
genocide linguistic genocide nothing
nothing of that so the Romans were
actually nice in from that perspective
and and so on so forth you will see
Roman language imposition in various
parts of the world the if you look at
the entirety of Europe except for
Eastern Europe you will see that the
Roman script is used in every country
even though it's a foreign script the
English script that you see here it's
not an English script it's a Roman
script it's a Latin script but yeah so
some of that has happened but overall
the Romans were not that destructive and
not that cruel comparatively
compared to the French or the British
now the French and the British were
christian powers and therefore there was
this whole monotheistic angle to their
conquests so uh when the French
conquered Egypt they used the pyramids
for target practice for their cannons
the they they did the they did target
practice of their cannons on the face of
the Sphinx and they were overall cruel
and destructive when it comes to the
British they tried to uh they this
almost successfully destroyed India's
education system imposed their third
rate education system on India which was
designed to uh you know churn out clerks
and peons and they tried their best to
destroy Hinduism and impose Christianity
which is now succeeding so the Romans
never did any of
that so overall the Romans were not that
bad now what about the French versus the
British well just look at the French
rule in various parts of India
pondicheri Etc they destroyed temples
and and built churches on top of them
the French they were
cruel so uh if if there was French rule
over India instead of British rule we
would be speaking French right now yes
we would be speaking French but it would
be the same India would not have been
better off under French rule it would
have been mostly the
same all right
McLovin says can you tell us about the
the Boeing controversy India has ordered
a huge number of Boeing aircrafts is
that a good idea to go ahead with that
deal oo
scary ah yes the boying thing so uh the
boing Dreamliner was it that F that
plane that there were like two or three
crashes because of a faulty Software
System which forced the nose down down
down the pilots would try and rest
wrestle it back but it just kept on
going down down down
because of a faulty Weather Vein or
something wind ve faulty input and there
should be redundancy of that sensor on
both sides but only one was there so if
that malfunctions you you're dead and
the software will override the pilot and
just keep on putting the nose down
because the the the wind sensor is
giving it false false data wrong data
because it is faulty and that's how
there was a crash in what Indonesia or
somewhere Malaysia Indonesia somewhere
there one in Africa and one maybe
somewhere else that's that's the
Dreamliner thing Dreamliner thing it's
it's a software problem some bunch of
idiots put in the wrong you know coded
the wrong software the wrong thing then
you've had other incidents with
boing uh Wheels falling off engines
malfunctioning doors blowing open in the
middle of the flight and and and other
stuff as well so that tells you that
there is something wrong
in uh the quality standards at Boeing
and it is alleged it's all about
diversity the what the Americans call
diversity we call reservations in India
reservations imagine you're a doctor
let's talk about the Indian equivalent
of the American diversity
H imagine you have an entrance exam for
becoming a doctor what NE yeah there's
some some something going on right now
and in some entrance exams you have like
90% reservations so you are a general C
category candidate you get excellent
scores but somebody with 10% less than
you can lepr over you over you and that
person has that person has got 10% or
15% or 20% less marks than you which
means that person doesn't really know
the subject well but you don't get the
seat that person gets the seat and that
person becomes a qualified
surgeon while while not being that good
at it do you want a doctor who is not
not good at his or her
job that's what reservations does to
India India needs to get rid of
reservations in certain things at
least
doctors Pilots would you like to travel
in a
plane where the pilot got in got the job
because of reservations would you like
to travel in the plane so that's kind of
what's happening with booing diversity
quotas and whatnot there was this big
controversy in South Africa Kevin
Peterson the the the the cricketer he
left South Africa because of this
diversity quota and and
stuff and uh we now have something like
that in the US so we seeing a decline in
the
standards of the work that's happening
in boing and it's now visible with all
these
incidents so that is the boing thing the
Dreamliner controversy was different and
what's happening now is different but
it's the same company boing and yes we
have ordered the large number of boing
aircraft uh uh well I don't know what to
say about
it I when I when I travel I look at the
make of the of the plane of the aircraft
is it Airbus yes good I
go now I don't know I I hope it just
goes fine but yeah it's it's kind of
worrying isn't
it uh that's what I would
say Raja choa says was Modi cabinet 3.0
formation and Ministry allocation a
mistake what's your take uh if you look
at the portfolios that have been given
to the various ministers there's a lot
of continuity so Dr J Shankar is once
again the foreign
minister uh and so on
so Mrs sitar Nalan is again Finance
Minister I think um Mr Amit sha is again
home minister and so on so there there's
a significant amount of continuity and
there are some reshu some people have
been
reshuffled uh and some of the new
coalition Partners have been given
portfolios and all that so I don't
really see too much of a controversy
over there I don't see any mistakes
there uh as long as you have a hard
Taskmaster at the top which is Mr Modi
and he gives the portfolios to various
ministers he's going to ensure that
they'll do the work so I don't see any
mistake over there I think it'll go fine
I think Mr Modi knows how to get people
to work and work well so that's that's
good for us so overall I don't see any
mistakes there I think I think it's
fine all
right Malik sad says can Breton Woods
hotel agreement type of thing happen in
case of World War I look the Bron Woods
agreement was something that happened in
1944 it was the essentially the formal
adoption by the world of the US dollar
as the world's Reserve currency that's
what it was and the US took control of
the Global Financial system essentially
that's what the Breton Woods agreement
was it happened in 1944 kind of in the
prude to the end of the second world war
so the second world war was destructive
I don't know how many million people
people died 7080 million people died
perhaps I don't remember the exact
number tremendous numbers of people died
India paid a lot in blood we did now so
that's the impact of World War II much
of the world was ruined and devastated
lots of people died but the Americans
were the big Winners and not just in the
war but they kind of took control of the
global economy that was the Britain
Woods agreement now if there's a World
War I first of all let's define World
War I World War I means the two largest
the two most powerful Nations fight and
everybody else gets involved so what are
the two most powerful Nations it's the
US and Russia not us China China is not
powerful hard power Russia is powerful
and what contributes majorly to Russia's
hard power nuclear weapons the world's
largest nuclear Arsenal and the means to
deliver those nukes anywhere they want
that's what makes Russia so powerful
Russia is a very powerful defensive
power its offensive capabilities are
ballistic missiles all right so if World
War II happens it means the US and
Russia fight each other obviously China
may also fight with Russia if it has to
and with the us the whole of NATO EU
everybody else will fight Japan South
Korea will get dragged into it so that's
a World War but it's essentially US
versus Russia and if the US and Russia
fight my dear friends it means that
nukes are going to
fly and once the nuclear exchange starts
it destroys the world the Americans want
to destroy India as well
so when World War II was ending Britain
Woods happen right when World War II is
ending it we'll be lucky to have a few
million humans alive on the
planet that's the scary thing about
World War I because World War I will
inevitably unfortunately involve nuclear
weapons and once a single nuclear weapon
is used there's going to be a chain
reaction and more will be used and then
more will be used and then they will all
be used up and then what's left nuclear
winter no sunlight for 10 years how many
humans Will Survive forget about Breton
Woods there won't be any anything left
so yeah scary scary and we it could
happen that's that's the scary part it's
not some hypothetical theoretical
scenario what's happening in Ukraine is
is really concerning the the West is is
pushing Russia further and further
against the wall they've given Ukraine
to go ahead to use NATO weapons now and
yeah the Russians are now sending
nuclear submarines to the Cuban to the
waters in
Cuba we are seeing the escalation of
tensions here
we don't want World War II but if World
War II happens it'll be the end of
civilized
existence no cell phones no
internet no electricity no television no
telephone
landlines no
traveling
no whatever what do you have
zato zepto nothing no Amazon everything
is over
you'll be lucky to be
alive so there won't be any Britain
Woods kind of agreement if World War II
happens there won't be any us
left okay Manel says we as we have the
ability to see only a limited section
limited uh part of the visible light
spectrum of the light spectrum of the
electromagnetic spectrum is it possible
that any organism might be able to see
the high band such as x-ray or gamma
rays we don't know of any organism that
can see gamma
rays but there are organisms that can
see uh light in the ultraviolet range of
the spectrum and maybe even infrared so
uh let's see what crows okay let's let's
go to the
uh let's see what some birds look like
ultraviolet
light so if we look at a crow
under ultraviolet light how do we see
crows crows are black right but some
birds have the ability to see in the
ultraviolet or Whatever frequency range
and they to those birds crows look like
that look like this
iridescent so yeah there you go crows
crows see the world in in this sort of
uh in this sort of light so we see the
the Mina bird as this dark brownish
colored bird but crows see the bird
looking like this you know bright bright
colors so yes that is true there are
animals there are birds even pigeons
look like
this in in ultraviolet Dr Light or maybe
U some birds can see pigeons in this
manner so the point is that we have
limited uh our vision is limited we can
perceive electr magnetic waves in a
certain range of the electromagnetic
spectrum but other animals Birds Etc can
see more more of the of the
electromagnetic spectrum than us but I
don't think they there's any organism
that can see in the X-ray range or the
gamma ray range gamma rays are extremely
dangerous to life because they they they
cause mutations they are extremely high
energy electromagnetic radiation it's
essentially
what what comes out of of uh nuclear
weapons and so on
so yeah so that's the
answer knowledge Seeker says can the
government identify them you mean the
fake the Bangladeshi infiltrators with
fake other cards they possess the
problem is that these other cards may be
real other
cards how do you know an other card is
fake they may be real other cards so
that is the problem the AAR card is not
a citizenship document but from the AAR
card you can make other documents and
you take these documents together you
can get a passport and that's that's
where you become a citizen so uh that is
the problem I don't know what the
solution
is
okay okay Shri ramachandra namaha says
China cares much about its demography
and culture Chinese population pref for
Mr shei despite him being a dictator and
what do you think about Miss Madame
milone is Italy's
president yes the Chinese care about
demography they they they care about uh
look the Chinese Communist Party cares
about staying in power and they know
that when it comes to abrahamic
religions people who uh practice
abrahamic religions they generally have
extra territorial extran National
loyalties the Chinese have known this
for a very long time the Japanese have
known this for a very long time
themselves the Mongols knew this so and
that is generally the purpose of
missionaries to convert
large large swats of population of a
nation's population to their foreign
religion and then use that to to do
regime change or or or get various kinds
of uh uh you know
benefits so the Chinese understand this
and that's why they don't tolerate non
ch
religions and all you know what they've
been doing doing to the ugur you know
what how they've been treating the
Christians whatever they have and so on
they don't see Asian religions as a
threat so they don't do anything against
Buddhism they there there was some some
uh persecution of the Fallon gong people
for whatever reason which is a Chinese
thing which has ties with Buddhism but
there is no persecution of
Buddhists or or Confucian people or
taist or whatever but there is
persecution of the UR and whatever else
so the Chinese government is a
dictatorship Mr she is a dictator you
can consider him to be an emperor the
current emperor of this dynastic cycle
the Dynasty is the Chinese Communist
Party Dynasty and the succession is non-
hereditary that's how it is and the
Chinese are okay with
this that's historically how China has
always been there's never been democracy
in China democracy is unnatural to China
it is it is foreign to China so the
Chinese are fine with having an emperor
what's wrong with having an emperor from
their perspective so they're fine as
long as they get a good life good living
standards and so on so forth why will
they
complain so yeah and of course nowadays
they are um the Chinese are are very uh
strongly promoting their culture which
is all about the national image and
Prestige and all that so that's the deal
so that's that's how it is in China what
do I think of Madame milone as a Italy
president I think she is a good
president obviously she has done nothing
about the demographic problems she has
done next to nothing about illegal
immigration coming in from certain
Nations so yeah she has failed at that
but apart from that she still is
reasonably
popular and perhaps she may be the best
leader they have right now when it comes
to Illegal immigration and not doing
anything about it I think there is
nothing she can do about it because
Italy is not a Sovereign Nation it is
under the EU it is also also a part of
NATO and it is also whether you realize
or not under permanent US military
occupation since 1945 so Italy is not a
Sovereign Nation even though it has
elections and blah blah blah so when it
comes to certain things like uh like
foreign policy well the it's all
mediated by NATO and and and the EU so
it's fine but certain things will be
dictated by the Americans and I think
illegal
immigration is kind of part is part of
that
so there's nothing Madame Melone can do
about that but apart from that she may
be probably the best leader they have
right now all
right the problem is appeasement um
which nation India uh if you're talking
about India I would not disagree with
you ranar banik says can everything in
the universe be explained through
mathematics well when it comes to the
physical
world the patterns and the
regularities in the universe are
mathematical in nature all the patterns
are mathematical in nature math is the
most parsimonious
expression of these patterns and
regularities so yes the physical
Universe the visible invisible physical
Universe all of it has mathematics that
underlies it's functioning that is true
but when it comes to things like love
and the soul and emotions I don't know
whether mathematics is behind that okay
I don't know about that so yeah some
things we may not comprehend right now
maybe we are not intelligent enough to
comprehend that but yeah there you have
it
okay basar katwal says what should be
the most appropriate and just response
to the rasi attack according to you and
great meeting with Jau dios okay we met
outstanding okay uh the Ry attack is the
terrorist attack in Jammu and Kashmir
right Jammu I believe or Kashmir
wherever what's the most appropriate
response first of all neutralize the
terrorists appr find them neutralize
them and if this continues then take the
fight to the source so terrorism comes
in from across the line of control right
so take the fight to the source and
teach them a few lessons that's the
right response eventually long term we
just keep growing we keep on
neutralizing terrorists we keep
on teaching them the lessons that they
need to learn and eventually as we grow
way larger P will come back to India
Pakistan will disintegrate eventually
and that's so long the the long-term
solution is for us to win on our own
that's what needs to happen
herel pradan says do you think if we
remove reservations the country will go
f grow faster of
course look I understand why
reservations have been put in place
because there are sections of society
that are
economically not well off there are
people living in poverty there have been
people people living in extreme poverty
all of this goes back to the 250 years
of British occupation in India and
before that the taric occupation of
India so India has had a terrible time
the past Thousand Years roughly and
because of that we have this horrific
problems in India so there are people
who are in extreme poverty people who
are in poverty people who are have been
marginalized so on so forth so they have
to be given opportunities so the
solution according to the great wise men
of India is to give reservations in
everything in in education in in jobs
blah blah blah all
that so what that does is that you may
be a terrible student but you will get
jobs and you will get seats in colleges
and Universities at the expense of those
who have studied really hard and who are
really good at what they're doing that
is going to create such frustration
tremendous amounts of frustration in
India and it's going to destroy the very
concept of Merit if a society does not
respect Merit the society goes nowhere
it's on the path to destruction so what
needs to be done I believe that those
who are are living in poverty who have
been
disenfranchised the past few centuries
or whatever and who are still suffering
from the consequences of that they
should be
given free
education okay they should be given the
same opportunities and they should be
given financial
assistance but giving
them seats in educational institutions
and and jobs while not being deserving
it's it's going to destroy Society so
give them financial assistance for the
next 20 years next 50 years if you want
give them financial assistance so that
they can compete on the same level as
everybody else you give them financial
assistance then what else do you need
right so that's what needs to happen for
a limited amount of time maybe 20 years
maybe 50 years whatever they can decide
so that's what we can do that would be a
just thing to do a right thing to do but
the reservations H they they will
destroy Society they are already already
Society the standards of the iits have
dropped abysmally in the early 2000s the
iits were among the best educational
institutions in the world when it comes
to science and technology today they're
not even in the top 100 top 200 that's
how badly we've destroyed the iats in
just in about two decades that's what
we've done because of because we brought
in reservations into the iats so I think
the reservations should go but no
politician will dare to touch
reservations because you are guaranteed
to lose elections because we Indians are
used to freebies right we want more for
nothing so yeah there we have
it okay dongar Singh Johan says what's
the mystery behind the Guna caves many
people have lost their lives there and
not a single trace of them has been
found that's interesting never heard of
it but let me go and Google it Guna
caves what is Guna caves
okay is where Devil's
Kitchen okay so it looks like some place
in where is it it's in Tamil Nadu Tamil
Nadu and uh so I don't know about the
story of what happened and what what the
history is but as you're saying many
people have lost their lives there and
not a single trace of them has been
found so there are some cave systems
that are very dangerous for human beings
in some caves you have carbon dioxide
it's fused with carbon dioxide you go
inside and it will be a deep cave and
you lose Consciousness and you just drop
down God knows how many meters and so on
so there are lots of things there are
certain caves where well that's a
different story you know Ebola and and
and uh marberg virus Etc they also came
from some caves in in Africa in the
Congo or something very dangerous
viruses emerged out of certain caves but
that's that's a disease when it comes to
instant death like you're saying it
could be because of carbon dioxide or
something or or some some gas that that
is prevalent in these caves I'm just
speculating out Al loud because I don't
know about the story of these caves so I
don't know I've not heard of these caves
I did not know until I read this
question by dungar Singh
Chan but there are caves which with in
various parts of the world that have
this this bad reputation of of being
very dangerous and there might be good
reasons for that so it's all about
patterns regularities that certain
things certain conditions may be
prevalent in some caves which are very
dangerous to human beings so either the
cave is very narrow and very deep it's
not been explored properly and people
generally go there without proper
precautions because it looks innocuous
and maybe in there there may be some gas
some something that that makes you
unconscious and then you fall somewhere
deep and you may never be found that's
speculation I'm saying but that is
plausible so that's what I can say
without knowing anything about the
caves
okay Richard says should one start doing
a job in their 20s or just continue
learning and upskilling like doing
masters from Germany who was also from a
middle class family look uh what would I
do I'll just say what I would do I would
say just keep on upskilling and all that
it's going to keep on postponing the
experience you can
get
um what matters in life is what you make
of it not to how many degrees you get
okay you may get a good master's degree
in Germany but after that what happens
where do you get a
job uh and a master's degree will take
what two
years so two years is not that much of a
time you may get good skills you may get
a better degree in so it's all about um
what what you are able to do with the
degree does the degree actually add some
value to you and help you get a better
job or should we just start off I would
say just start off doing a job and get
as much experience as possible and do a
master's degree parttime on the
side so you get a master's degree you
get the thing obviously you to work
harder but yeah you got to work harder
you can't succeed without working harder
than
others um I am a big believer in
starting
to work as soon as possible ideally you
should start start to work in your when
you're 16 17 ideally but the education
system is such that you can't do that
you are forced to just keep on studying
until you're in the mid almost mid 20s
ideally you should be in the job market
by your by the time you're 16 17 18 so I
would say
look if this master's degree that you're
referring to if it gives you great job
prospects guarantees you great job
prospects then you should do it but if
it is like like one more thing on one
more feather in your cap but then there
is no guaranteed good job job placement
or whatever then I think it's a waste of
time you can do a job start a job right
away and do a master's degree on the
side part-time or distance education or
whatever that way you can even do two
master's degrees if you want so yeah
that's what I would say it all depends
on your specific
circumstances on your past track record
on what the Master's Degree offers you
and so on but uh the rule of thumb from
my perspective is that you need to be
financially independent at as early an
age as
possible so that you no longer have to
depend on family or relatives or
whatever you're entirely independent and
then you have options so you should aim
to become financially independent at as
early an age as possible that is the
rule of Thum and then you can factor in
all the other things into
that tmai says another terrorist attack
in Duda happened right now fourth one in
four days okay maybe it's time to teach
the pakistanis a lesson maybe but this
time they'll be expecting it so how do
we play it well the leader will decide
Mr Modi the ball is in your court but
yeah the pakistanis seem to be um asking
for it aren't they maybe they will get
what they're asking
for so aara says when we talk about
education system reforms what are we
specifically talking about root learning
with skills or something else this is a
deep deep deep deep deep to topic okay
let me show
you okay let me show you what I'm
talking
about let's go to my YouTube
channel uh let me put that on the
screen and if you want an answer if you
are seriously interested in the answer
then I'll tell you what to look
at okay uh so let's go down let's go
down
we are looking at an older version of as
abijit older
episodes of as abijit one second it's
okay
so
uh okay episode 28 episode 30 episode
31 these
are long episodes of asit dedicated only
to educ ation especially episode 30 if
you want the answers watch the entire
episode ideally all three episodes
that's where you will get the answer I
cannot give you an answer in like 30
seconds or 2 minutes there is so
much that is part of education but yes
root learning is a huge problem you
can't you don't learn anything through
Ro root learning nothing goes in your
head you to understand Concepts and
apply those Concepts in solving problems
there's so much more so those episodes
if you are genuinely interested in
knowing the problems of the education
system I have spoken about them I also
given
Solutions if somebody wants to implement
them because I understand education I've
been part of the education system for a
very very long time I've seen it inside
out so I know what the problems are I've
given I've I've laid out what the
problems are and I've given Solutions if
somebody wants to implement them so
watch those episodes
okay Muhammad is says is it true dur
that during Mansa musa's pilgrimage to
Mecca while in Egypt he spent so much
gold that he diluted its value and
plunged Egypt into an economic crisis
that is I I believe that's true so manam
Musa was this King in Mali I forget
which century he lived in it's it's at a
time that is before the European
destruction of
Africa so Ali was a very rich Kingdom
and he is reputed to have been the
world's richest
individual uh I don't know what was his
net worth in today's dollar value maybe
500 billion or something tremendously
rich
person okay and and he went on a
pilgrimage to Mecca and he was
just Distributing gold dust and whatnot
to wherever he was going in whichever
land he was passing through so he spent
a lot of gold in Egypt he and he and he
flooded the market in Egypt with so much
gold that gold lost its value he diluted
the value that's how inflation happens
when there's too much of
something then then the value goes down
so that's what it did so yes Mana Musa
was the world richest individual maybe
Elon Musk or somebody may be richer than
him today but he was at that time
historically the world's richest ever
individual that we know off from a
western
perspective and uh yeah so I I have a
video on Mansa Musa let's let's let's
let's if you want to see and and and
some people believe that if Mansa Musa
was so rich how can you claim that India
was the richest civilization in the
world right
so yes Mansa Musa was Mali Empire richer
than India so I have kind of gone into
that myth that because he was the
richest man in history that means that
Mali was richer than India that's the
logic that some people use so i' I've
addressed that in that video
all right all
right what
else
uh okay science will
do being enlight says you look great in
short hair I saw your old
video I I'm a lazy guy I just don't want
to cut my hair I'll just leave it long
and it looks short from here right you
don't you don't really see the long hair
here it looks like it's short so it's
fine it's no problem
right
uh okay science all right today we can
take some science I I'm always happy to
do that g says gravity is theorized to
be a curvature of space TY but what
exactly is spacetime is it a fundamental
entity or an emerging property or
something more basic SpaceTime is
something we can't imagine because it's
four-dimensional we know space right
three dimensions length breadth and
height three Dimensions now add the
fourth dimension of time which we can
kind of kind of vaguely perceive and
that becomes a four dimensional fabric
of space time you can't visualize it
because we can only visualize
threedimensional things but yes the
presence of mass curves space time and
the curvature of SpaceTime causes tells
Mass how to move so it's a what exactly
is space time is the question here what
exactly is space time is it a
fundamental entity or emerging property
of something more basic I would say most
likely it depends on which perspective
you're looking
at it's probably a fundamental entity it
is the stage on which the Universe plays
out its role it's it's a stage on which
the objects in the universe interact
it's a stage four-dimensional stage so
from that perspective it's a fundamental
entity it's it's the very fabric of the
Universe from a string theory
perspective M the Theory
perspective uh SpaceTime is
just uh from look String Theory you can
have 10 Dimensions 11 Dimensions 26
dimensions and
uh and and and our universe is simply
one of the a lower dimensional brain
they say brain membrane within a higher
dimensional
bulk so from that perspective it's not
even a fundamental thing it's something
something that is lower dimensional than
the actual higher dimensional bulk in
which the universe exists and that's
something we cannot
perceive and so on so look it's it's all
Theory right when it comes to M Theory
spring Theory super String Theory etc
etc it's all Theory we don't have any
evidence of that but general relativity
we know it works we have evidence of
that so from the perspective of general
relativity SpaceTime is it's a
fundamental
itty it's it's it's the very Fabric and
structure of the
Universe I have already answered thrust
vectoring why are you asking
again
uh all right
um getting lots of questions repeated
for some reason okay let's go to the
very end
yes uh
okay let's see
some okay toi says if a war happen with
China we'll definitely lose I mean if no
one helps us we'll lose why do people
think we stand a chance with China in a
head-on conflict be it a long war or a
short war you to
understand the circumstances of China's
occupation of Tibet yeah see China I
agree is four times more powerful
roughly than India from a hard power
perspective four times which means that
if we
have whatever strength we have they have
four times the strength in the resources
roughly so from that perspective we
stand no chance but you to understand
that they cannot bring all their assets
to Bear against India if there's a war
first of all they have so many enemies
they have made enemies everywhere they
are worried about Japan the worried
about South Korea they have to bolster
North Korea there is a balance of power
they have to maintain and they have to
maintain the balance of power whatever
exists in the South China Sea they have
to keep on encircling Taiwan they take
out all those assets from those places
to Bear bring to bear against India they
become vulnerable in those places which
is why out of all of their assets they
can bring in at least at most a third or
a fourth against
us and those assets are half a continent
away to bring to transport them all the
way to the India Tibet border is going
to take a long time and a lot of effort
it's not easy that's one secondly they
have very little lines of communication
and Supply chains when it comes to Tibet
occupi Tibet there have maybe one or two
highways that connect Tibet with
mainland China and one Railway line
that's it if India takes that out Tibet
is disconnected from
China and then there are problems in
Tibet Tibet is at a very high altitude
which means that fighter planes taking
off from there have to take a lower load
but Indian fighter planes just 100 kilm
away can take off with full load and
then the Chinese Assets in occupied
Tibet are all exposed because there is
no Forest cover at all there are lots of
advantages India has which we don't
realize so if a war happens India has to
ensure firstly that it is fought on
Chinese occupied Tibetan territory not
Indian Territory you have to take the
war to Chinese occupied territory
because history tells us the history of
the past 2,000 years tells us that China
doesn't do well when it has to fight a
defensive War this is a pattern that
recurs again and again and again in
history firstly take the fight to the
Chinese occupied territory secondly the
war cannot last long it has to be a
short sharp War India has to ensure that
cut off the Chinese communication
lines the railway line and the couple of
Highways and then let's see what they do
and take out their fighter play as
quickly as as possible with missiles of
course they also have missiles it's not
as as easy as it sounds and then there
is always the last option the Chinese
know they can't afford to tempt
India into exercising the last option
the Chinese have spent so much effort
energy time in building up their economy
the last 40 years you think they are
willing to lose that in one shot like
that of course if they threaten India
beyond the point IND will have to use
the last option China can't afford that
so understand this India is no pushover
and a war in the Himalayas is not fought
with technology the terrain you go there
just go to the Himalayas go to those
areas of of the world you can't use
technology there tanks won't work there
drones won't work there what will work
there human beings it's about quality of
human
beings so India has advantages you you
should not be the I don't know why some
Indians are so pessimistic don't be so
pessimistic look at the situation look
at the circumstances look at the
strength and weaknesses of both sides
China may have four times as strength as
India but China has 10 times the enemies
as India China is encircled you don't
understand the Americans have encircled
China the Chinese cannot afford to take
away their their forces from those
places they can bring in only a quarter
or maybe a third of their for forces to
Bear against India and of course they
can induce Pakistan to attack India at
the same time so India will have to face
a twoof front for situation but we can
deal with
Pakistan and then you deal with China
and you take the fight to their
territory it's easier said than done I
know it's difficult but the situation
isn't as Bleak as you make it sound or
you imagine it is yeah of course we'll
be we'll have our back against the walls
against the wall it'll be a difficult
task but yeah so so be it if it happens
and there could be a war with China in
the coming years so India has to
militarize India has to militarize in
such a manner that if the Chinese are
fool Hardy enough to go to start a war
against India they
will end up facing a situation they have
not
expected
okay
okay uh let's see
McLovin says can you suggest some good
comedy movies or shows comedy movies I I
like comedy movies good i' I've one
movie that
never fails to make me laugh no matter
how many times I see it is the mask Jim
Carry watch any Jim Carry movie you
you'll have a good laugh there is that
then what else do we have Mars Attacks
science fiction plus comedy haha The
Fifth Element science fiction plus
comedy haha and what else ah how can I
not how can I forget this one the party
the party it's a movie from 1968 if I'm
not
mistaken uh the
party
okay uh let's put that on the screen
right there's a movie from 1958 or
something uh
1968 1968 the
party uh Peter sers one of the greatest
actors of all time he plays the role of
an Indian actor in
Hollywood okay and that movie is so
ridiculously funny incredibly
funny and it's probably the only
Hollywood movie which is not Hindu
phobic but has an Indian
character the party
1968 the main character is Indian he's
played by a white guy in Brown face and
that movie that is not Hindu phobic he
actually the B character and the good
guy it's the one of the funniest movies
I've seen in my life I'm not sure how
where you'll find it I'm sure you can
find it if you're resourceful enough the
party 1968 watch it one of my favorite
movies Peter
Sellers um donger sing Johan says how
can some can someone go mentally
abnormal insane by overthinking can
overthinking actually impact the brain
do scientists go mad by overthinking I'm
not sure how Insanity
happens uh scientists think all the time
a scientist can stare out of the window
for six hours and people will say he's
doing nothing the guy is thinking and is
working a scientist staring out of a
window for six hours is working
intensely but he looks like he's just
looking
out overthinking doesn't make anyone
insane there are people who think all
the time there's always something going
on in there something serious something
constructive that doesn't make you
insane I don't know what makes you
insane
um so there are certain illnesses like
schizophrenia that that for example John
Nash uh the mathematician who won a
Nobel prize in economics he had
schizophrenia and schizophrenia is about
a delusional thing I believe so that's
one form of mental abnormality or
Insanity delusional thinking
schizophrenia hearing voices seeing
things that aren't there
hallucinations and the paranoid thinking
so I'm not really sure what insanity is
and how it happens and what are the
causes schizophrenia is is a genetically
inherited condition I believe and uh so
that's one form of that insanity or
mental
abnormality some people have depression
like luck bpan and yeah
depression but that's not Insanity
that's just depression that's a whole
different story and who else do we know
who went insane I can only think of John
Nash um so I'm not sure about the the
the mechanics of insanity or or mental
abnormality schizophrenia is the only
thing I can think of right now not sure
how it happens but overthinking
doesn't uh cause anyone to go mad for
sure I would
know I would
know
uh you a fan of analog say three ways S2
it's fun I don't even know what analog
horror is I'm scared to put it on the
screen right now I wonder what will come
up but yeah okay interesting I I'll
check it out don't know what it is
digital Horror versus analog horror not
sure overall I'm not a big fan of horror
it's either this this Gore and splatter
and stuff jump scares or it's
psychological horror which kind of is
depressing at times I'm I'm more a fan
of fun stuff comedy movies and and
positive stuff and all that is not my
favorite genre I mean i' I've seen in
some of the classics what is it red drum
what was it red
drum Jack
Nicholson um The Shining I've seen that
all the classics I've seen The
Exorcist uh what else the six sense it's
not really horror it's a good movie
actually so on but um I seen the ring
which is kind of
depressing yeah
so okay I I'll check it out analog
horror D Johan says have a
mustach
yes sure I can try if you
like
okay Joseph peda says the US Empire is
built and run by developing violence
sanctions genocides and subjugation of
people from other nations geopolitics is
like the law of the Jungle and the
fittest live absolutely it's the law of
the Jungle and that is geopolitics and
we shall end this session on this very
correct assessment of what geopolitics
is all
right there always more interesting
questions
um but I guess I will stop here because
otherwise it'll go on
forever retes says why change accent I
don't know it happens sometimes because
I'm not depressed and I'm not mentally
insane so I like to have fun sometimes
yes I
like uh why you look like Mexican I not
Mexican I Indian Mexicans Indians look
very similar do you know that when I I
remember I've been to the us a few times
and
sometimes I was once in a
casino for whatever reason should try
things right this guy next to me is like
drunk and he's like what God you
believe and he thought I was Mexican and
somewhere else in a train station
somewhere of all places a guy comes to
me and starts talking to me in Spanish
he thought I I'm I'm Mexican so yeah
where you have there you have have it
Indians Mexicans look similar we have
the same skin color similar features
similar eye color similar hair color so
yeah all right okay that's all we have
crossed 2 hours 13 minutes way past our
time so I'm going to end it here but
thank you so much for all your questions
thank you for participating in askit and
we shall and we shall continue this so I
will see you very soon in the next
session which will be on Saturday until
then take care and don't forget to keep
raising your standards thank you bye-bye
see you soon